<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on NixBytes</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on NixBytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          After dabblingly in a few programming languages like javascript, bash, and python, I finally biting the bullet and trying out C++, as low-level features and high-level abstraction, I figure this would boost my coding skills and get me closer into more development. So far, the language is not as scary as many make it be. Let touch on a few things on why C++ is good to learn.
First The Community # The language itself has many followers, and many business use C++ for varies of reason.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aws Cloud Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/aws-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/aws-cloud/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          AWS Cloud # The AWS Command Line Interface (CLI) is a powerful and convenient tool that allows you to manage and control your AWS services with ease. By using a unified interface, you no longer need to switch between multiple tools or dashboards to manage your cloud infrastructure. Instead, you can control all your AWS services from the command line, which provides a streamlined and efficient approach to managing your cloud environment.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Shell on IPad or IPhone</title>
      <link>/posts/linux-shell-on-ipad-or-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linux-shell-on-ipad-or-iphone/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Hello Fellower Moles, thier is a great tools that haves a linux shell on moble devices. The new Linux command line iSH app on iPad or iPhone. With iSH Shell is a Linux shell for iOS that uses an x86 emulator to run a simplified version of Alpine Linux on IOS. You can install packages and additional software directly into iSH with the Alpine package manager.
Why Alpine Linux you say?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          So Linux Academy is offering a great course called Mastering Regular Expressions. After taking a few video course and video, I have to say learning more about regular expressions is more important than ever. Perhaps a few regexes (regular expressions) is fine for simple tasks, but for complex problems, having a deeper knowledge on many levels can boost your technical skill to a new level especially with the need for big data.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 22:02:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Unveiling the Mysteries of Technology: A Security Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Tale # Welcome to the Realm of Technological Wonders! # Hello, fellow tech adventurers! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to take you on a journey through the depths of technology, where I wear the dual hats of a Security Engineer by day and a passionate coder by night. This blog is my sanctum, a place where I unravel the dark mysteries and hidden powers of Linux/Unix systems, coding, and cybersecurity.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>