<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on NixBytes</title>
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on NixBytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>After dabblingly in a few programming languages like javascript, bash, and python, I finally biting the bullet and trying out C++, as low-level features and high-level abstraction, I figure this would boost my coding skills and get me closer into more development. So far, the language is not as scary as many make it be. Let touch on a few things on why C++ is good to learn.
First The Community The language itself has many followers, and many business use C++ for varies of reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aws Cloud Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/aws-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/aws-cloud/</guid>
      <description>AWS Cloud The AWS Command Line Interface (CLI) is a unified tool to manage your AWS services. With just one tool to download and configure, you can control multiple AWS services from the command line and automate them through scripts. Now in day scripting is mostly tie to automation. as I alway say, if you can type, you script it and finally you can automate. That why shell interface is so vital in today technology,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Shell on IPad or IPhone</title>
      <link>/posts/linux-shell-on-ipad-or-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linux-shell-on-ipad-or-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Hello Fellower Moles, thier is a great tools that haves a linux shell on moble devices. The new Linux command line iSH app on iPad or iPhone. With iSH Shell is a Linux shell for iOS that uses an x86 emulator to run a simplified version of Alpine Linux on IOS. You can install packages and additional software directly into iSH with the Alpine package manager.
Why Alpine Linux you say?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>So Linux Academy is offering a great course called Mastering Regular Expressions. After taking a few video course and video, I have to say learning more about regular expressions is more important than ever. Perhaps a few regexes (regular expressions) is fine for simple tasks, but for complex problems, having a deeper knowledge on many levels can boost your technical skill to a new level especially with the need for big data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery Badges Project</title>
      <link>/projects/jquerybadgesproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/jquerybadgesproject/</guid>
      <description>Use jQuery to Fetch and Show Code School Badges Using Ajax I build a personal web page that displays the courses which I completed on Code School by pulling data from the Code School website.
GitHub Link jQuery Badges Project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects This is list of of my projects, language and technology that I have work with. In each page the projects with a summary and github links.
Page Links  Cpp System Monitor CppND Route Planning jQuery Badges   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>