<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on NixBytes</title>
    <link>/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on NixBytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>After dabblingly in a few programming languages like javascript, bash, and python, I finally biting the bullet and trying out C++, as low-level features and high-level abstraction, I figure this would boost my coding skills and get me closer into more development. So far, the language is not as scary as many make it be. Let touch on a few things on why C++ is good to learn.
First The Community The language itself has many followers, and many business use C++ for varies of reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>So Linux Academy is offering a great course called Mastering Regular Expressions. After taking a few video course and video, I have to say learning more about regular expressions is more important than ever. Perhaps a few regexes (regular expressions) is fine for simple tasks, but for complex problems, having a deeper knowledge on many levels can boost your technical skill to a new level especially with the need for big data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects This is list of of my projects, language and technology that I have work with. In each page the projects with a summary and github links.
Page Links  Python HTTP Services BirthDay CountDown Wizard Battle Weather Cliet Guess Number Python File Searcher Bhyves WebSite Weather Journal App Cpp System Monitor CppND Route Planning  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>