<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on nixbytes</title>
    <link>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on nixbytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/learning-c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>After dabblingly in a few programming languages like javascript, bash, and python, I finally biting the bullet and trying out C++, as low-level features and high-level abstraction, I figure this would boost my coding skills and get me closer into more development. So far, the language is not as scary as many make it be. Let touch on a few things on why C++ is good to learn.
First The Community The language itself has many followers, and many business use C++ for varies of reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumpstart Python</title>
      <link>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/jumpstart-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/jumpstart-python/</guid>
      <description>Python Jumpstart by Building 10 Apps &amp;ldquo;The Python Jumpstart by Building 10 Apps Course&amp;rdquo; is a great path to get started on learning python and some of the core features. Micheal Kenndy explains each topic in details and with good examples. Python is growing, and the demand for the skill set is high peak right now. Python Jumpstart will help anyone to get started on the language. I enjoy doing these small projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:25:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/mastering-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>So Linux Academy is offering a great course called Mastering Regular Expressions. After taking a few video course and video, I have to say learning more about regular expressions is more important than ever. Perhaps a few regexes (regular expressions) is fine for simple tasks, but for complex problems, having a deeper knowledge on many levels can boost your technical skill to a new level especially with the need for big data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 16:51:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nixbytes.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello, This is my first Post for discussing technology, and its uses started to blog to speak about the passion I have for Linux/Unix, Python and Open Source technology. I will Post my thought with no scheduled time frame, and I am thinking of adding a new post on my twitter account if you wish to follow me feel free to do so. Hope you enjoy my blog post and my thought on tech.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>